Every dirty dataset is dirty in its own unique way.
每个污染数据集都有各自的污染特色
Trying to list every specific quality issue here in this lesson is, therefore futile.
因此本课程列出每一个具体的质量问题是徒劳的尝试
But we can categorize them.
但是我们可以对问题进行分类
These categories of data quality are called data quality dimensions.
数据质量类别被称为数据质量维度
But there's little agreement among researchers as to what these dimensions actually are,
但研究人员对于何为维度 几乎没有共识
or even if they should be called dimensions.
甚至不确定是否应称其为维度
For example, this source has six dimensions.
例如 这里提到了六个维度
This source calls them data validity
这里则称其为数据有效性规则
rules and actually has some different terms compared to the first source.
实际上与刚刚看到的六个维度相比有一些不同的术语
This source calls them data quality aspects and lists eight.
这里称其为数据质量角度 并列出了八个数据质量角度
And this source says there are seven dimensions.
这个提到了七个维度
So some sources list more, others less.
这样一来 数据质量的类别不一而同
Some call them aspects,
有些人称其为角度
metrics, rules, measures, dimensions.
有些人称其为指标、规则、措施、维度
There's no real solid standard.
因为并没有真正固定的分类标准
Everyone does seem to agree on these next four though.
尽管如此 几乎所有人似乎都认同以下四个类别
And the vast majority of data quality issues that I've come across,
而且我遇到的绝大多数数据质量问题
can be sorted into these four buckets: completeness,
也均可以归为这四个类别 即完整性
validity, accuracy, and consistency.
有效性、准确性和一致性
These dimensions can help guide your thoughts when assessing your data.
在评估数据时 这些维度可以引导你的思路
These are listed in decreasing order of severity which will make sense shortly.
这四个类别按照严重程度的降序排列 其意义如下
So completeness.
首先是完整性
Do we have all of the records that we should?
我们拥有完整的记录吗？
Do we have missing records or not?
是否漏掉某些记录？
Are there specific rows,
有没有缺少某些行
columns, or cells missing?
列或者单元格？
An example of this in our dataset for this lesson is the missing hba1c change variable,
本课程的数据集中的一个例子是缺少 hba1c_change 变量
represented by NaN's here.
表示为 NaN
Next, validity.
然后是有效性
We have the records but they are not valid.
有记录但记录是无效的
More technically, it doesn't conform to a defined schema.
从技术层面讲 它不符合确定的模式
First of all, a schema is basically a defined set of rules for data.
模式是关于数据的一套确定的数据规则
This schema can be enforced by real world constraints,
这个模式可能是现实世界的约束
like you can't have negative height.
比如你不可能有负数的身高
You can't be negative 66 inches tall for example.
如负的 66 英寸的身高
These individuals aren't in this dataset, but just imagine.
这个数据集中不存在 我们只是想象一下
But this schema can also be a specific schema just for your table or database.
但是该模式也可以是用于你的表或数据库的特定模式
A good example of this is a primary key in a database,
数据库中的主键就是一个很好的例子
or unique key constraints in tables.
或表中的唯一键约束就是一个很好的例子
In this dataset, that means there can't be duplicate patient IDs.
在这个数据集中 指的是不可能有重复的患者 ID
If systems are good, they aren't always though,
如果系统没有问题 虽然并不总是如此
invalid record creation will be denied.
将拒绝创建无效记录
For example, in this dataset,
例如在此数据集中
if you try to create another patient with the patient ID of one,
如果尝试用患者 ID 1 创建另外一名患者
you'd be denied, ideally at least.
理想情况下应该至少会遭到拒绝
Another example in this dataset of invalid data is our zip code data here.
这里的邮政编码数据是无效数据集的另一个例子
This is invalidated because zip codes must be five digits in an integer.
这个是无效的 因为邮政编码必须是由五位数字构成的整数
Whereas this one is actually a float and sometimes four digits.
而这里实际上是一个浮点 有的是四位数
Now, accuracy.
接下来是准确性
Inaccurate data is wrong data that is valid.
不准确的数据是有效的错误数据
It adheres to the defined schema, but it's still incorrect.
虽然遵循了确定的模式 但仍然不正确
This data doesn't conform to a gold standard, if you will.
也可以说 该数据不符合优质标准
For example, looking at weight in this table.
比如这张表中的重量
Imagine at the scale that each patient was measured on was slightly
想象一下 如果每名患者的测量均出现轻微错误
faulty and overestimated each patient's weight by five pounds.
比实际体重高出 5 磅
The weight's slightly off, but still valid.
体重虽然略有偏颇 但仍然有效
Inaccuracy issue that we already identified was
前面我们已经发现的不准确问题
the height entry for this patient being 27 inches.
是这名患者的 27 英寸身高
27 inches is technically still valid.
严格意义上来将 27 英寸身高是有效的
It's possible for an adult human to be 27 inches tall.
一个成年人有可能 27 英寸高
The shortest adult ever measured 21 inches approximately.
因为世界上最矮的成年人约为 21 英寸
And since the inclusion criteria for
由于本临床试验的纳入标准
this clinical trial required patients to be at least 18 years old,
是至少年满 18 岁的患者
we can ignore the possibility of this being a child's height.
所以我们可以排除这是某个孩子身高的可能性
So again, 27 inches is possible, but it's unlikely.
重申一次 27 英寸身高是可能的但不太可能用在此处
And we already know that the correct height is actually
而且我们已经知道
72 inches and that these digits were switched around.
正确的高度实际上是 72 英寸 这两个数字被交换了位置
So this is an accurate data.
72  英寸才是一个准确的数据
And finally, consistency.
最后是一致性
Inconsistent data is both valid and accurate.
数据不一致并不影响其有效性和准确性
But there are multiple correct ways of referring to the same thing.
同一事物有多种正确的方法来表示
We want consistency in fields that represent
但是我们希望在表中或关联表中
the same data across tables or within tables.
同一数据的字段中保持一致性
We're looking for a standard format basically.
我们想要看到标准格式
In this dataset, we've identified inconsistent representations of state,
在这个数据集中我们看到了各州不同的表示方法
full state name versus abbreviation.
有的是全称 有的是缩写
For example, California and CA,
例如加州 California 和 CA
or New York and NY.
纽约 New York 和 NY
That's inconsistent.
均属于不一致的情况
This inconsistency means we can't analyze our dataset based on state.
这种不一致意味着我们无法根据各州来分析我们的数据集
At least until we clean this issue.
除非我们解决这个问题
So those are the four main dimensions of data quality.
以上就是数据质量的四个主要维度
Again, the order of these here is in decreasing order of severity.
再强调一下 这里的顺序是按严重性的降序排列的
Completeness issues means we don't have the data.
出现完整性问题说明我们缺少某些数据
Valid data exist but,
有效性问题说明存在数据
it doesn't adhere to a schema.
但该数据不符合特定模式
Inaccurate data is present invalid but incorrect.
准确性问题说明数据存在、有效但不准确
And inconsistent data is present valid and accurate,
一致性问题说明数据存在、有效、准确
but it has multiple representations.
但使用了多个表示方式
Again, you can use these dimensions to help
在你评估数据时 这些维度
guide your thought process when assessing your data.
会帮助引导你的思维过程